Olawole Ogunfunminiyi frankfurtmacmoses@gmail.com +1(832) 8150073



PROFILE / SUMMARY

Frankfurt is an experience and a business minded software engineer and data scientist; able to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advance data driving methods, willing to experiment with custom algorithms for business applications and data products.

EXPERTISE

- Data mugging / cleaning and Descriptive Analysis with R tidyverse and other R packages
- Big Data Queries and Interpretation with
- Machine Learning Algorithms with R and Python – sklearn, pandas, numpy and R caret package
- Reproducible Research and Report Generation with R
- Data visualization with R ggplot2 and python ggplot implementation

- Data Driving Application with Oracle
- Oracle Weblogic and Glassfish server configurations for Oracle apex 5.1 and other JEE applications
- Extensive knowledge of Linux operating system commands and scripting
- Versatile with object-oriented design/programming with java/Python
- Knowledge of Business component development with JEE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Java Developer/Data Analyst Source Support, Houston TX

August 2018 – February 2020

- Furnished executive leadership team with insights, analytics, reports and recommendations enabling effective strategic planning across all business units, distribution channels and product lines.
- Developed intricate algorithms based on deep-dive statistical analysis and predictive data modeling that were used to deepen relationships, strengthen longevity and personalize interactions with customers.
- Analyzed and processed complex data sets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Participate actively in the complete software development lifecycle, including performance analysis, design, development, and deployment of machine learning model to applications
- Ensure solid, minimal-defect code by performing unit testing with JUnit test cases and through rigorous integration testing of the entire application
- Responsible for parsing and merging datasets
- Trained R and Python Programmers regarding applicable regulatory guidelines and programming activities.

Senior Java Developer **MTN**

February 2014 - March 2018

- Utilized Struts2, Spring MVC and HibernateJPAframework for development
- Involved in Design Development and Implementation of business Applications using Java/J2EE Technologies.
- Participated in development of Web application to manage Unix build stations using Java, MVC, javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, plink.exe for sending remote commands, bash, Oracle Database
- Lead the team that developed balloting application in Java/J2EE technologies like JSP, Hibernate, Spring, Struts, Java Servlets, AJAX, JavaBeans, JNDI, JMS, XML, web service using IDEs like Oracle JDeveloper.
- Migrated external DNS from Server 2003 to BIND running on Linux.
- Deployed code in ApacheTomcat and Weblogic server to production server

Build Web Services for the enterprise applications using SOAP and writing DTD, Schema, Namespaces, XSL, Xpath, Xlink, XQuery, XHTML and SAX, DOM and JDOM parsers

Oracle PLSQL Developer

ChamsSwitch Limited

June 2009 - November 2013

- Involved in logical modeling and physical modeling of applications with oracle data modeler.
- Developed Stored Procedures, Functions, Packages and SQL Scripts using Oracle PL/SQL.
- Involved in creation of Conceptual Modeling covering all the business requirements.
- Loaded the data into database tables using SQL*loader from text and excel files.
- Developed data model, SQL Queries, SQL Query tuning process and Schemas.
- Created SQL*plus reports as per client's various needs, and developed business objects with PLSQL.
- Developed SQL scripts for Referential Integrity check, which checks validity of incoming data with master tables in database.
- Involved in updating procedures, functions, triggers, and packages for validation and loading of data into target table based on the current requirement.
- Involved in Design Development and Implementation of business Applications using Java/J2EE Technologies by creating "customized views" on top
 of oracle tables.

Software Developer

New Horizons Computer Learning Centre

June 2006-November 2009

- Team Leader, and Senior Instructor New Horizons / Babcock University joint program. Taught Object Oriented programming and SQLServer in Babcock University.
- Developed application on Microsoft Dot Net Platform: Test Engine for Students Performance Evaluation using Microsoft.Net 2.0 Platform with Microsoft SQLServer.
- Project Management Team and Co Developer for E-learning Application for Nigeria Bottling Company (NBC) and FCMB.
- Trained corporate organizations: Con-Oil Plc, Diamond, Bank First Bank Plc, EFCC etc in JAVA, XML, VB.NET, SQL SERVER, PL/SQL and ASP.NET

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION:

Graduate Diploma Computer Science – Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria 2017

Thesis Title: Comparative analysis of Pig and Hive

Master of Business Administration (MBA), Business School Netherlands 2015

Thesis Title: Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics In Osun State, Nigeria

BSC Soil Science – Obafemi Awolowo University – Nigeria 2003

CERTIFICATIONS

2008	Project Management Professional, PMP (ID: 1212004)
2007	Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java EE 1.4 Platform (SCWCD) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated
2006	Sun Certified Programmer for Java Platform (1.4) (SCJP) Awarded by Sun Microsystems Incorporated, Now Oracle Incorporation
2006	Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) Awarded by Oracle Incorporation

MOOC Certificates

John Hopkins University

Data Science Toolbox Getting and Cleaning Data R Programming Exploratory Data Analysis Statistical Inference Regression Model Reproducible Research

University of California, San Diego

Introduction to Big Data Analytics Hadoop Platform and Application Framework Introduction to Big Data